BE HEAVY · FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Résidence Ouarsenis, Akid Lotfi, Oran, Algeria

□+213551081911 | 🗷 caddydz4@gmail.com | 🏕 caddydz.github.io | 🖸 CaddyDz | 🖹 salim-djerbouh | 🛅 CaddyDz | ¥ saly3301



Summary.

Full-stack web developer and DevOps/SysAdmin. Participated in developing and maintaining large web based applications. 6+ years experience specializing in the backend development, infrastructure engineering, CI/CD pipelines automation. Super nerd who loves Vim, macOS and Linux and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools when the need arises.

Skills

DevOps Heroku, Linux, Docker, Vagrant, Sentry, Travis Cl, GitHub Actions, CloudFlare, Stripe, Algolia, Pusher, Vonage

Laravel, NodeJS, MySQL, Redis, REST API, Swagger, Postman Back-end

Front-end VueJS 2/3, VueX/Pinia, Nuxt, WebPack, Vite, HTML5, CSS3, Vuetify Material, Bootstrap, jQuery

Programming PHP, Javascript ES6, C#, Python, Shell Scripting

Jira, Figma, ClickUp, Notion, VCS (Git), Unit Testing QA and TDD, ACL, DAL, DTO Engineering

Languages English, French, Arabic

Work Experience _____

Salesforce, Inc San Francisco, California

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

June. 2021 - December 2021

- Wrote the full test-suite for Unit, Feature and Browser QA tests.
- · Developed and maintained CI/CD pipeline on GitHub with actions and Heroku deployments as well as review apps on branches connecting everything to Jira development board.
- · Audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.
- Built Redis based queue system and moved long processing operations to background jobs.
- Worked on end-to-end features as part of a larger team, took responsibility of instantly pushing bug fixes as they arrive on Sentry and Bugsnag.
- · Building campaign manager assets through Cloudinary API was dying in the background and it was hard to debug and tell what went wrong, I integrated Laravel Horizon & a queue worker dyno on Heroku that immensely helped developers maintain a healthy codebase.
- Managers had the futile task of manually inviting users from Salesforce CRM to the campaign builder, I wrote a script to parse users export as CSV files, I created an admin panel where a manager can upload the CSV and it send out email invitations for people to register and because the project is deployed in the Heroku platform that Salesforce owns, I wrote a bash script to execute seeders and artisan commands on the release phase.
- Users leave their campaign builder form open in the office so I wrote a frontend code to detect inactivity and send an API request to auto logout and invalidate session (saving current unsubmitted work) at a configurable interval.
- Added a way for managers to flag users as (free access) so they don't get charged via Stripe.
- · Sometimes logos get rendered incorrectly on top of certain backgrounds, I used Cloudinary API to intelligently invert or place the logo on a
- Certain developers and HTML designers kept on misspelling the brand name Salesforce, so I created a GitHub action that combs through the entire codebase and automatically correct the spelling with a bash script that uses grep and sed.

Order Spark Remote, USA (Freelance)

BACKEND DEVELOPER, DEVOPS LEAD

- Built management portal UI and backend (Laravel Nova)
- Built marketing site API
- Handled all DevOps infrastructure and software architecture
- Organized, secured, cleaned up and documented system resources.

Remote, USA (Freelance) One Potato, Ltd

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

- · Setup a staging server/environment.
- · Redesigned the deliveries page.
- · Fixed frontend VueJS bugs.
- Refactored and cleaned up parts of the codebase.
- Developed a weekly total billing component.

Oct. 2022 - Present

Oct. 2022 - Jan. 2023

Remote, USA

Backend Engineer, DevOps

Jan. 2022 - May. 2022

- · Debugging and maintaining a Django based admin panel.
- Connecting uploaded audio file briefs to AWS S3 with Amazon Alexa.
- · Maintaining deployments on Heroku.
- Audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.

Shyfter, SRL.Brussels, Belgium

BACKEND ENGINEER, DEVOPS ASSIST

Feb. 2021 - Aug 2022

- Integrated government services with compliance to security requirements like Dimona and audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.
- Advised and moved the company's backend from serverless Google Cloud Run to Google dedicated servers which resulted in a faster performance and response time as well as to GitHub for a more streamlined deployment pipeline and CD productivity.
- Worked on customer exclusive features and requirements.
- Built Redis based queue system and moved long processing operations to background jobs.
- · Migrated legacy codebase from pure procedural PHP to resusable service classes resulting maintainability.
- Refactored code base reducing algorithmic complexity and also enforced coding standards for consistency.
- Built a printable dynamic GATT documents and assisted frontend team on API consumption.

Zidweb, LLC. Oran, Algeria

CO-FOUNDER, CTO AND LEAD DEVELOPER

Feb. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Provisioned an easily manageable hybrid infrastructure(Digital Ocean Droplets + On-premise) utilizing IaC tools like Sentry and OpenVPN
- · Manage all DevOps and third party services integration (CloudFlare, Forge, Algolia, Pusher, Vonage)
- Implemented, documented RESTful API server for directory listing application
- Wrote and deployed several small scale apps like shopping carts.
- Restructured a +40 million records database of automotive spare parts catalog and implemented a web interface for it
- Created Backend in Laravel + Frontend in NuxtJS for an ELO Boosting gaming service.

Didata LLC. Zürich, Switzerland

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER March. 2020 - April. 2020

- Wrote example testing data seeders for BioLab research application
- Implemented an ACL architecture for Backend API
- · Wrote mutations mapping module for state management following the Flux pattern for the Frontend application
- Implemented several CRUD models

Honors & Awards.

INTERNATIONAL

2016-2023 Top %4, Overall Stack Overflow members

Internationa

Amsterdam,

2018-2020 **Top #37**, PHP ranking GitHub awards

Netherlands

DOMESTIC

2020 **1st Place**, Most Active GitHub contributor

Algeria

Presentation

GDG Conference Blida, Algeria

PRESENTER FOR < MACHINE LEARNING THEORY>

Nov. 2017

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Introduced the theory of machine learning genetic algorithms with an analogy of evolutionary biology}$
- Introduced how machine learning algorithms work with an implementation of an SAT resolver in symbolic regression

CSC Club VCS event

Blida, Algeria

SPEAKER < PRODUCTIVE GIT AND GITHUB WORKFLOWS>

May. 2017

• A step by step guide & live demo of GitHub teams workflow, from forks to clones to issues and pull requests to merges and releases.

OpenMinds Linux install party

Algiers, Algeria

SPEAKER < A LOOK INTO THE KERNEL INTERNALS>

Apr. 2017

 $\bullet \ \ \text{A brief talk about the Linux kernel source tree and subsystems with a short introduction to OSDev}$

Education

Lounici Ali University

Blida, Algeria

Sep. 2013 - Jan. 2016

Final year English literature

- American history, civilization & literature
- Studied English linguistics and works of Noam Chomsky